Finding Aid for the Lucile, Lady Duff-Gordon Drawings LSC.0624
UCLA Library Special Collections
- 75, pen sketch of back view on bottom right corner, Lucile signature [long blue overcoat with yellow buttons and yellow cuffs and collar]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 81; Foxing on upper left-hand corner, smudge on bottom left and right corners, "No. 1" written in ink on top left corner, peeled spot on upper right-hand corner. (Box 9)
- 76, pen sketch of back view on bottom right-hand corner, Lucile signature, [olive green-colored pleated dress with lace sleeves and collar and buckled belt]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 82; Foxing on bottom left-hand corner, grease spot on bottom right-hand corner, peeled spot on upper left-hand corner. (Box 9)
- 77, colored sketch of back view on bottom left-hand corner, Lucile signature, [gray and black layered dress with lace sleeves trimmed with black]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 83; Foxing on upper left-hand corner and bottom right-hand corner. (Box 9)
- 78, pen sketch of back view on bottom left-hand corner, [light purple and pale blue dress with pink top and green ribbons, and fur-trimmed cape with flower designs and pink and green trimmings]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 84; Foxing on top and bottom edges and middle left-hand side, colored smudge on bottom right-hand corner, bent upper left- hand edges and bottom, indentation on upper right-hand corner and bent upper and lower right-hand corners. (Box 9)
- 79, pen sketch of back view on bottom left-hand corner, [matching two-piece blue and pink dress blue flower prints and yellow vest-like front and fur trimmings]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 85; Foxing on bottom edge and upper and middle left-hand area and upper right-hand edge, smudges on middle left-hand side, peeled area on upper left-hand corner, bent upper left and right-hand corners, indentation on upper right-hand corner. (Box 9)
- 80, pen sketch of back view on bottom right-hand corner, Lucile signature, [orange-peach silver laced layered dress with matching jacket with fur trimmings]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 86; Foxing on bottom left-hand and right-hand area and right-hand edge, bent upper right-hand corner. (Box 9)
- 81, pen sketch of back view on bottom right-hand corner, [floral printed, off-the-shoulder dress with blue, pink, and purple ruffles trimmed with red trimmings and green ribbon on front, with matching fur-trimmed hat]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 87; Foxing on bottom left-hand and right-hand areas, bent upper right-hand corner, white-out and grime in middle area. (Box 9)
- 82, pen sketch of back view on bottom right-hand corner, [orange-peach off-the-shoulder dress with silver printed floral design and matching train, fur trimming across the front, yellow ribboned sash]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 88; Foxing on middle, left, and right-hand areas and bottom left-hand area, glue-like residue along top edge, peeled spot in lower middle area, bent on all four corners, smudge on upper right-hand area. (Box 9)
- 83, pen sketch of back view on bottom left-hand corner, [flouncy Irish-green dress with printed green flower designs and green striped bodice, and sheer gathered short sleeves]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 89; Foxing on middle left and right-hand areas, smudging on bottom area, bent upper and lower right-hand corners, white out in mid-left area, peeled upper edge. (Box 9)
- 84, pen sketch of back view on bottom right hand corner, [lime-green, silver-printed design with blue ribbons on white slip underneath]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 90; Foxing on lower right and left-hand areas and in middle left-hand area, peeled upper left-hand area, dark-brown grime spots on middle area around sketch. (Box 9)
- 85, pen sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, [shaded gray tulle afternoon dress with black printed designs and sheer flared sleeves]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 91; Foxing on top middle and bottom right-hand areas, smudging on bottom left-hand corner, ink smudges around sketch, bent upper left and right-hand corners. (Box 10)
- 86, [off-the-shoulder blue gathered dress with two distinct bouquets of flowers in front, with sheer lace trimmed bodice]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 92; Foxing on left side and upper and lower right-hand areas, smudges on bottom left and right-hand areas, bent upper right and bottom left-hand corners. (Box 10)
- 87, pen sketch of back view on bottom right-hand corner, Lucile signature, [pale pink, off-the-shoulder ruffled dress with green ribbon underneath, and blue, purple, and pink ribbons cinching the waist]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 93; Foxing on middle and upper left-hand area, grease spot on bottom left-hand corner, smudging on middle right-hand and upper left-hand areas, "5" written in pencil on upper right-hand corner. (Box 10)
- 88, pen sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, Lucile signature, [white satin-like dress with fur trimmings and train, and feathered black hat]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 94; Foxing on upper and lower left-hand areas, peeling on top edge, smudging on upper left-hand area. (Box 10)
- 89, colored sketch of back view on bottom right-hand corner, Lucile signature, [dress with green plaid bodice and sheer skirt with elliptical green designs with flowers]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 95; Foxing on bottom left and upper right-hand areas, bent upper left and right-hand corners and bottom edge, peeled upper left-hand corner. (Box 10)
- 90, pen sketch of back view on bottom left-hand corner, Lucile signature, [Asian-styled blue and pale pink dress with silver designs and light turquoise ribbon in front]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 96; Foxing on upper left-hand area and bottom right-hand area, peeled upper left-hand corner, bent upper left and right hand- corners and bottom edge, smudging on upper and middle left-hand areas, and on middle area of sketch. (Box 10)
- 91, pen sketch of back view on bottom right-hand corner, [off-the-shoulder lime green ruffled dress with blue-gray bodice and flower design in middle front]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 97; Foxing on bottom and middle left-hand area, major tear along upper area and upper right-hand side, water spot on middle right-hand area, smudging on all four corners. (Box 10)
- 92, pen sketch of back view on bottom left-hand corner, Lucile signature, [fur trimmed and gold-banded salmon-red coat over white dress with gold design prints]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 98; Foxing on middle and bottom left-hand areas and upper right-hand area, smudging on bottom right-hand corner, watercolor spot on middle right-hand area, peeling on upper middle area. (Box 10)
- 93, colored sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, Lucile signature, [pale pink layered dress with flared sleeves, pale blue bodice, and pale blue ribbon on skirt]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 99; Foxing on upper right and bottom left and right-hand corners, peeling on upper left-hand corner, tear on upper left-hand side, bent upper right and bottom left-hand corners, smudging on upper right and bottom left-hand corners. (Box 10)
- 94, pen sketch of back view on bottom left-hand corner, Lucile signature, [long pink jacket with buttoned cuffs over pale pink dress and peach trimmings]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 100; Foxing on upper and bottom left-hand and bottom right-hand corners, smudging on bottom left and right-hand corners. (Box 10)
- 95, pen sketch of back view on bottom left-hand corner, Lucile signature, [pale blue dress with ribbons on waist and matching jacket with fur trimmed cuffs and fur collar and matching fur trimmed hat]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 101; Foxing on upper left-hand and lower right-hand areas, pen marks on bottom right-hand corner, water color stains on lower middle area of sketch. (Box 11)
- 96, pen sketch of back view on bottom left-hand corner, Lucile signature, [grey-printed high collared black coat with fur trimmings and grey tassels with blue-purple lining]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 102; Foxing on middle left-hand area, slight smudging on upper middle and right hand area and bottom right hand corner. (Box 11)
- 97, pen sketch of back view on bottom left-hand corner, Lucile signature, [brown coat with fur trimmed cuffs and collar and gold and black banded lining and tie with light blue dress underneath and blue hat with brown veil]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 103; Foxing on bottom edge, smudging on right and left-hand sides, slightly bent bottom right-hand corner. (Box 11)
- 98, pen sketch of back view on bottom right-hand corner, Lucile signature, [sheer white and pale pink ruffled dress with yellow fur trimmed top and green and blue sashes]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 104; Foxing along left and right-hand sides, smudging on upper right-hand corner, peeled top edge, bent upper right and bottom left-hand corners. (Box 11)
- 99, pen sketch of back view on bottom left-hand corner, [grey layered dress with fur trimmings with flared sheer sleeves and blue and green trimmed collars and cuffs]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 105; Foxing on upper left-hand and middle right-hand areas, smudging on bottom and upper right-hand areas, peeled area on bottom right-hand corner. (Box 11)
- 100, pen sketch of back view on bottom left-hand corner, [off-the-shoulder dress with grey and white lace layered over orange skirt with yellow and orange train and ribbons across the chest]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 106; Foxing along right-hand and bottom sides, colored smudge on middle right-hand area, bent on all four corners, striated top edge, peeled area on middle right-hand area. (Box 11)
- 101, pen sketch of back view on bottom left-hand corner, Lucile signature, [layered brown dress with buttoned top with collar and fur trimmings and brown and dark teal along the bottom]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 107; Smudging on bottom right and middle left-hand areas. (Box 11)
- 102, pen sketch of back view on bottom right-hand corner, Lucile signature, [high collared buttoned white dress with black and white banded lining and fur trim around collar and sleeves with fur barrel muff]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 108; Foxing on bottom right-hand corner, smudging on bottom and left-hand side, peeled area on lower middle area, white-out and black smudge on upper-middle area. (Box 11)
- 103, pen sketch of back view on bottom right-hand corner, Lucile signature, [pale green dress with pleated bodice and criss-crossed ribbons on top with buttoned sleeves and red hat]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 109; Foxing along middle, smudging on right-hand and bottom sides. (Box 11)
- 2/16, pen sketch of back view on upper left-hand area, Lucile signature, [blue layered dress with pink ribbons and trimmings with ruffled sleeves and yellow hat with long pale green ribbon]., 1915/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 110; Foxing on bottom left and right-hand corners, bent top left and right corners, striated top. (Box 11)
- 104, pen sketch of back view of top on lower right-hand corner, [white dress with buttoned top and ribbon, sheer sleeves and blue waist]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 111; Foxing on middle left-hand area, bent upper right-hand corner. (Box 12)
- 105, pen sketch of back view, [sheer pale green dress with silver printed designs with silver colored waist and purple drapings over skirt]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 112; Foxing on middle left-hand area and upper right-hand side. (Box 12)
- 106, pencil sketch of back view on lower right-hand area, [white dress with sheer sleeves and tassels in front]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 113; Foxing on bottom and middle left-hand areas and middle top edge, peeling in top area, colored spot on bottom left-hand corner, smudge on upper right-hand area. (Box 12)
- 107, pencil sketch of back view on bottom left-hand corner, [blue-green layered dress with white collar and blue ribbons along the front]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 114; Foxing on left-hand side, smudges on sketch. (Box 12)
- 108, pencil sketch of back view of top on lower right-hand side, [white top with pink trimmings and ribbons and sheer sleeves with white skirt with buttons at waist]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 115; Foxing on upper right-hand area, bent upper right and left-handed and bottom left-hand corners. (Box 12)
- 109, pen sketch of back view on bottom left-hand corner, [grey dress with sheer banded sleeves and ruffled collar and blue ribboned hat]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 116; Foxing on middle left-hand area and top edges, smudges on lower right-hand area on sketch. (Box 12)
- 110, [high fur collared plain front blue dress with blue and black sash and fur cuffs and matching fur hat with green tassel]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 117; Foxing on top and left sides, bent upper right-hand and bottom left-hand corners and middle right edge. (Box 12)
- 111, pencil sketch of back view on bottom left-hand corner, [silver printed green and turquoise sheer dress with floral printed pants underneath and long green ribbons tied at wrists and matching green hat w/ long sheer veil covering lower half of face]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 118; Foxing on top and upper right-hand sides, bent upper left-hand corner, smudging on middle right-hand area. (Box 12)
- 112, pen sketch of back view on bottom right-hand corner, [sleeveless pink and peach colored layered dress with flowers at waist and long sheer veil]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 119; Foxing on top edge and bottom right-hand corner, color marks on middle right-hand area, bent upper right-hand corner. (Box 12)
- 113, pen sketch of back view on bottom left-hand corner, [cream colored dress with green, blue, and multi-colored speckled bands around waist with multi-colored speckled designs on bottom of dress and sash around lower waist and on matching jacket ]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 120; Foxing on upper right-hand area and top edge, peeled area on left-hand side. (Box 12)
- 114, pen sketch of back view on bottom left-hand corner, [deep v-neck white dress with pale olive green designs and high-waisted belt and sheer sleeves]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 121; Foxing on upper right-hand area and along top edge, peeling along top edge. (Box 13)
- 115, Mrs. Carlton signature, [sleeveless royal blue dress with grey flower prints and sheer thigh length ruffles]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 122; Foxing on top and bottom right-hand areas nd middle left-hand side. (Box 13)
- 116, [long pink jacket with flower and lace trimmings over white dress]., 1916; UCLA Drawing No. 123; Foxing on upper right-hand area. (Box 13)
- 117, pen sketch of back view on bottom left-hand corner, [blue dress with long banded sheer sleeves with blue printed designs]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 124; Foxing on all four corners. (Box 13)
- 118, pen sketch of back view on bottom right-hand corner, LDG signature [gold-printed blue top with fur lined collar and pink, red, and yellow tassels hanging from cuffs with teal colored skirt and matching vest with fur trimmings and tassels]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 125; Foxing along all four sides, smudging on middle right-hand area, tear on bottom right-hand corner, bent upper right-hand corner. (Box 13)
- 119, pen sketch of back view on bottom right-hand corner, [silver printed orange dress with purple fur trimmed cape with tassels]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 126; Foxing on upper left-hand side and along top edge, white out and smudge around sketch, bent upper left-hand corner. (Box 13)
- 120, pen sketch of back view on bottom left-hand coner, Lucile signature, "Lucy Duff Gordon 3/8/16, No.17 Guranzza" [Spanish style light yellow turtleneck dress with black, white, and orange patterned cuffs and matching tasseled shawl]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 127; Foxing on top and upper right-hand area. (Box 13)
- 121, Lucile signature, [sheer pale turquoise sleeveless dress with blue patterned designs underneath and long ribbon with flowers on chest]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 128; Foxing on upper right and left-hand areas. (Box 13)
- 122, [sheer gold printed turquoise dress with criss-cross in hip area and short veil]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 129; Foxing on upper left-hand area, bent upper right-hand corner, white out and smudge in upper middle-area around sketch. (Box 13)
- 123, pen sketch of back view on bottom right-hand corner, [pink and yellow flower printed sheer dress with silver patterned trimmings and high-waisted turquoise, green, and magenta colored sashes]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 130; Foxing on upper left-hand edge, peeled area in upper right-hand corner, smudge on bottom right-hand corner, striated top edge. (Box 13)
- 124, colored sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, [square fur designs on long brown winter overcoat with magenta high layered collar and cuffs; silver printed flowers on body of coat]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 131; Foxing along top, right and bottom edges, and middle left area, smudging on mid-lower area and lower left-hand area, bent upper left and right-hand corners, cut along right-hand corner, scratched top edge. (Box 14)
- 125, pencil sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, [long brown and black overcoat with wide collar and big cuffs, and buttons down the middle]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 132; Foxing along top, right, and bottom edges, and lower left-hand area, smudging in middle right-hand area, bent upper left- hand corner, slightly bent left-hand area, striated top edge. (Box 14)
- 126, pen sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, Lucille signature and "LDG," [sky blue colored nightgown robe with pink lining worn over a white nightdress with pink bow and sash]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 133; Foxing along top and right edges, and left-hand corner, smudging in lower left-hand area, bent upper right-hand corner, striated top edge. (Box 14)
- 127, pencil sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, [off-the-shoulder lime-green ruffled dress with blue, pink, and yellow trimmings on bodice]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 134; Foxing on upper left-hand area, upper right-hand edge, lower left-hand corner, and middle area, bent left-hand corner, striated top edge. (Box 14)
- 128, [long-sleeved dress with silver bodice and pink silver design printed skirt, with orange-pink sash tied around bodice and long pink sash tied around waist, long animal-fur scarf slung over right shoulder]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 135; Foxing on top right-hand edge, lower right-hand and middle areas, smudging on upper and lower left-hand corners, colored mark on middle left-hand area, striated top edge. (Box 14)
- 129, pen sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, Lucy Duff Gordon signature written in red ink and Lucile signature, "C'est-pour voas!!" [wintergreen colored dress with crème-colored sheer sleeves and fur trimming, matching fur cap]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 136; Foxing along top edge, upper right-hand edge, and middle left-hand area, smudging on upper and lower right-hand corners, striated bottom edge, glue-like residues on top edge. (Box 14)
- 130, pen sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, [long white overcoat with light-blue undertone, high folded collar with black and white tassels trimming the collar and bottom hem of coat, wide black bands around cuffs]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 137; Foxing along top and bottom edges and middle left-hand area, smudging on upper right-hand area, bent upper left-hand corner, striated top edge. (Box 14)
- 131, Lucy Duff Gordon signature and date written in red ink, ""Djer-Kiss" No. 14," [silver design printed coat with purple and green ribbons in front, pink and orange hems with floral design, brown fur trimming, flowy blue and pink dress underneath]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 138; Foxing on upper left-hand corner and bottom right-hand corner, smudging on bottom left and right-hand corners, and middle left and right-hand areas, striated bottom edge. (Box 14)
- 132, pen sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, [reddish orange colored robe with black trimming, silver design printed long brown sash]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 139; Foxing along top edge and upper left-hand edge, smudging on lower right and left-hand corners and upper left-hand corner, striated top edge. (Box 14)
- 133, pen sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, [sleeveless long pink top with gold diamond shaped prints over white dress with floral designs, matching pink with gold diamond shaped printed bandanna-like cap]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 140; Foxing along top and left edges, smudging on lower left-hand corner, bent upper left-hand corner, striated top edge with glue-like residues. (Box 14)
- 134, "Happiness," [long pale pink sleeved blue dress with ruffles and white designs on skirt portion, blue and light green sash around bodice with flowers in middle, ribbon designs on inner pale pink dress]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 141; Foxing along left edge and bottom right-hand corner, smudging on bottom left and right-hand corners and top right-hand corner, glue-like residues on top edge. (Box 15)
- 135, pen sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, Lucy Duff Gordon signature, [long sleeved light gray-brown dress with floral designs, banded cuffs, and hand muff with yellow lining, blue, yellow, and gray-brown colored hat]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 142; Foxing along top and right edges, smudging along bottom and left edges, bent upper left-hand corner, glue-like residues on top edge. (Box 15)
- 136, pen sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, Lucile signature and Lucy Duff Gordon signature with date, "No. 6 "A Solemn Thought"," [black dress with brown and black plaid long sleeves and brown plaid skirt underneath, white ruffled collar]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 143; Foxing along bottom edge, left middle area, and top right-hand edge, smudging on bottom left-hand corner and middle left and right-hand areas, slightly peeled top edge. (Box 15)
- 137, pen sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, [long pale blue robe with silver design prints, long blue ribbons with silver tassels at the end, and pale pink sash]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 144; Foxing on upper left and right-hand edges and middle right-hand edge, smudging on middle left-hand area, bent upper left and right-hand corners, peeled top edge. (Box 15)
- 138, [black sleeveless, form-fitting dress with designs and poofy, transparent gray skirt on top]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 145; Foxing on bottom and top left-hand corners, right-hand area, and middle left-hand areas, smudging on upper right-hand edge. (Box 15)
- 139, pen sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, Lucile signature and "LDG" signature in ink, [forest green two-piece dress suit with wide-buckled belt and high fur-trimmed collar and cuffs, long and flat purple and blue hat]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 146; Foxing along top and bottom edges, and middle left-hand areas, smudging along bottom edge and middle right-hand edge. (Box 15)
- 140, pen sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, Lucile signature and Lady Duff Gordon signature, [long gray-blue overcoat with dark green buttons, matching skirt with black band designs, dark green and black belt with matching cuffs]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 147; Foxing on upper right-hand edge, lower right-hand area, smudging on bottom right-hand corner and middle and upper right- hand areas. (Box 15)
- 141, pen sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, LDG signature, [off-the-shoulder orange dress with silver flower prints, sheer sleeves with yellow, green, and silver colored tassels hanging form sleeves]., 1916/Autumn; UCLA Drawing No. 148; Foxing on middle left and right-hand areas, smudging on lower edge and upper right-hand area, top edge slightly striated. (Box 15)